{
	"name": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary",
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "Air bubbles in the arterial blood vessels.",
			"back": "arterial air embolism"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "An impact on the body by objects that cause injury without penetrating soft tissues or internal organs and cavities.",
			"back": "blunt trauma"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "A phenomenon in which speed causes a bullet to generate pressure waves, which cause damage distant from the bulletâ€™s path.",
			"back": "cavitation"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "A brain injury that occurs when force is applied to the head and energy transmission through brain tissue causes injury on the opposite side of original impact.",
			"back": "coup-contrecoup brain injury"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "The slowing of an object.",
			"back": "deceleration"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "Resistance that slows a projectile, such as air.",
			"back": "drag"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "An evaluation tool used to determine level of consciousness, which evaluates and assigns point values (scores) for eye opening, verbal response, and motor response, which are then totaled; effective in helping predict patient outcomes.",
			"back": "Glasgow Coma Scale score"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "Awareness that unseen life-threatening injuries may exist when determining the mechanism of injury.",
			"back": "index of suspicion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "The energy of a moving object.",
			"back": "kinetic energy"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "The forces, or energy transmission, applied to the body that cause injury.",
			"back": "mechanism of injury"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "Emergencies that are not caused by an outside force; illnesses or conditions.",
			"back": "medical emergencies"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "Trauma that affects more than one body system.",
			"back": "multisystem trauma"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "Injury caused by objects, such as knives and bullets, that pierce the surface of the body and damage internal tissues and organs.",
			"back": "penetrating trauma"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "The product of mass, gravity, and height, which is converted into kinetic energy and results in injury, such as from a fall.",
			"back": "potential energy"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "Any object propelled by force, such as a bullet by a weapon.",
			"back": "projectile"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-16",
			"front": "Pulmonary trauma resulting from short-range exposure to the detonation of high-energy explosives.",
			"back": "pulmonary blast injuries"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-17",
			"front": "A scoring system used for patients with head trauma.",
			"back": "Revised Trauma Score"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-18",
			"front": "The path a projectile takes once it is propelled.",
			"back": "trajectory"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-19",
			"front": "Emergencies that are the result of physical forces applied to the body; injuries.",
			"back": "trauma emergencies"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-20",
			"front": "A score calculated from 1 to 16, with 16 being the best possible score. It relates to the likelihood of patient survival, with the exception of a severe head injury. It takes into account the Glasgow Coma Scale (GCS) score, respiratory rate, respiratory expansion, systolic blood pressure, and capillary refill.",
			"back": "trauma score"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-21",
			"front": "The eardrum; a thin, semitransparent membrane in the middle ear that transmits sound vibrations to the internal ear by means of auditory ossicles.",
			"back": "tympanic membrane"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-25-tag-vocabulary-card-22",
			"front": "The measure of force over distance.",
			"back": "work"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-25",
		"label": "Chapter 25"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}